Finding aid for the Lamis vs. Doyle and Sachs collection of court records, 1986-1990 LSC.2208
UCLA Library Special Collections
Lamis vs. Doyle and Sachs collection of court records
1986-1990
UCLA Library Special Collections
Lamis, Patricia
LSC.2208
2.5 linear feet (5 boxes)
Judith M. Doyle became a therapist in 1977, and was executive director of One in Long Beach, Inc., which runs a gay and lesbian service center. She was a chairwoman of the AIDS Walk/Long Beach and is one of the founders of the city's annual gay pride parade and festival. The collection documents the civil suit brought by the plaintiff, Patricia Ann Lamis against the defendant(s) Judith Manley Doyle and Lilian K. Sachs as well as the proceedings of the California state Board of Behavioral Science Examiners concerning the eventual loss of a license to practice on the part of Judith Manley Doyle for her sexual relationship with her patient Patricia Ann Lamis. The bulk of the collection is made up of depositions and transcripts of proceedings.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Provenance unknown. This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW) and the UCLA Library.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9973814823606533
Biography/History
Patricia Ann Lamis filed a civil suit against Judith Manley Doyle and Lilian K. Sachs in 1986, and also filed a complaint to the state Board of Behavioral Science Examiners against Doyle.
Judith M. Doyle became a therapist in 1977, and was executive director of One in Long Beach, Inc., which runs a gay and lesbian service center. She was a chairwoman of the recent AIDS Walk/Long Beach and is one of the founders of the city's annual gay pride parade and festival.
Scope and Content
The collection spans four years and two separate legal proceedings. It documents a civil suit brought by the plaintiff, Patricia Ann Lamis against the defendant(s) Judith Manley Doyle and Lilian K. Sachs, as well as the proceedings of the California State Board of Behavioral Science Examiners, concerning the eventual loss of a license to practice on the part of Judith Manley Doyle for her sexual relationship with her patient Patricia Ann Lamis. The bulk of the collection is made up of depositions and transcripts of proceedings.
Related Online Items Available
Portions of the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives Subject Files have been digitized and are available online: June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives Subject Files (863 items)
- Plaintiff (Patricia Ann Lamis) Responses to Interrogatories propounded by Defendant (Judith M. Doyle), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Interrogatories propounded by Defendant (Judith M. Doyle) for Plaintiff (Patricia Ann Lamis), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Deposition of Judith M. Doyle, September 5, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Deposition of Patricia Ann Lamis, September 12, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Deposition of Patricia Ann Lamis (2), September 22, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Scope and Contents note
  Second session.
- Deposition of Patricia Ann Lamis (3), September 22, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Third session.
- Deposition of Lilian K. Sachs, December 2, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Research, 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Contains research and discovery materials for the lawsuit including social security disability claims from Patricia Ann Lamis, reports and notes by various doctors of Patricia Ann Lamis and published materials regarding 'sexual intimacies' between therapists and patients.
- Deposition of Maurice W. Black M.D., March 5, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Deposition of Lilian K. Sachs (2), August 18, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Witness Examination: Nancy Lyle, December 1, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Witness Examination and deposition of Nancy Lyle, the former partner of Patricia Ann Lamis.
- Deposition of Dorothy Leach Ed.D., February 4, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Deposition of Danille Ford, June 24, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Deposition of Jerome Leff, June 23, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Deposition of Jerome Leff, former employer of Patricia Ann Lamis.
- Deposition of Garilynn Wadleigh, July 1, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Deposition of Helena Bartok, August 2, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Deposition of Doreen Carol Auriemma, July 11, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Board of Behavioral Science Examiners, April 26, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Board of Behavioral Science Examiners, April 28, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Board of Behavioral Science Examiners (Duplicate), April 25, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Board of Behavioral Science Examiners, April 27, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Board of Behavioral Science Examiners, September 25, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Board of Behavioral Science Examiners, September 26, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Partial Transcript of Proceedings: Board of Behavioral Science Examiners, September 27, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Deposition of Hannah Lerman PhD, June 1, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Deposition of Jacqueline C. Bouhoustos PhD, June 4, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Deposition of Eugene Malitz MD (Copy), July 5, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Deposition of Sharon Eve, April 19, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Partial Transcript of Proceedings: Board of Behavioral Science Examiners, April 21, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Transcript of Proceedings: Board of Behavioral Science Examiners, April 24, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)